<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>the tunnel &#8211; Springfestatx</title>
	<atom:link href="https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/tag/the-tunnel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:18:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>41 workers came out one by one from the blocked tunnel</title>
		<link>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/41-workers-came-out-one-by-one-from-the-blocked-tunnel/</link>
					<comments>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/41-workers-came-out-one-by-one-from-the-blocked-tunnel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the tunnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/?p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tuesday night around eight o&#8217;clock. Jharkhand laborer Vijay Horo was the first to come out of the blocked tunnel in Uttarkashi, Uttarakhand on a wheeled stretcher. In a moment, victory cheers started around him. Chief Minister Pushkar Singh Dhami wore the northerner around his neck. Union minister former army chief VK Singh was the witness. ... <a title="41 workers came out one by one from the blocked tunnel" class="read-more" href="https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/41-workers-came-out-one-by-one-from-the-blocked-tunnel/" aria-label="More on 41 workers came out one by one from the blocked tunnel">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Tuesday night around eight o&#8217;clock. Jharkhand laborer Vijay Horo was the first to come out of the blocked tunnel in Uttarkashi, Uttarakhand on a wheeled stretcher. In a moment, victory cheers started around him. Chief Minister Pushkar Singh Dhami wore the northerner around his neck. Union minister former army chief VK Singh was the witness. They pulled Vijay to their chest. That photo was caught in the media. The whole country breathed a sigh of relief after the anxiety was over. 17 consecutive days of continuous work is successful.</p>



<p>It was possible to bring out 41 people one by one before half past nine. All the rescue team including Chief Minister Dhami said that every worker is healthy. Their morale is also strong.</p>



<p>The chief minister himself raised the light of hope on Tuesday afternoon. This tunnel collapse was the most difficult challenge of his political life. 17 days ago on November 12, the 4.5 km tunnel collapsed. 41 workers from different states were trapped in it. From that day and night, various organizations were engaged in rescue work. Machines were brought from abroad. In came the experts who conduct rescue operations in such disasters. The attention of the entire country turned to this area at the foot of the Himalayas.</p>



<p>The news of the auger drilling machine brought from the United States becoming ineffective came as a big bad news for the countrymen who were in the swing of hope and despair. Foreign experts said that Christmas will come before the end of the new rescue phase. But the impossible was achieved within two days. The workers of the country cleared the tunnel manually with shovels and trowels and installed two and a half feet diameter concrete pipes. An iron pipe is installed in it. Through that pipe, disaster management personnel reached the stranded workers earlier in the evening. According to their advice, the arrested workers were dragged out one by one by putting them on a wheel stretcher. The prayers of the whole country were successful.</p>



<p>The rescued workers were first taken to the local hospital. A special ward has been opened there. All kinds of medical facilities have been kept. A helipad has been constructed next to the district hospital, so that any worker can be flown to the All India Institute of Medical Sciences in Hrishikesh.</p>



<p>After the successful completion of the rescue, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said in a message on social media, &#8220;This rescue has left everyone in the country emotional. I would like to say to the detained friends, your patience and courage have inspired all of us. After a long wait, they will be reunited with their families, it is a great relief. The patience and courage shown by their family during this difficult time is unparalleled.&#8217;</p>



<p>Union Road Development Minister Nitin Gadkari said that it has been decided to check the status of all the under-construction tunnels in the country. He said, the country learned a lot from this disaster.</p>



<p>This fact was also learned, where the machine failed, the infamous workers of India brought incredible success. Risking their lives in adverse conditions, they have managed to do the impossible by removing the collapse of the tunnel by hand and laying the pipe.</p>



<p>Despite the resolution of the rescue operation, the larger question remains. It has made the people of the country face the question of how rational the development by destroying nature is. The tunnel collapse that left so many workers dead is part of Prime Minister Narendra Modi&#8217;s &#8216;Char Dham&#8217; project. The project aims to connect the state&#8217;s four main pilgrimage sites of Kedarnath, Badridham, Gangotri and Yamunotri by building all-season roads and widening conventional roads for devout Hindus in Uttarakhand. But while doing so, the countrymen may have to face the fury of nature, this collapse indicated that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/41-workers-came-out-one-by-one-from-the-blocked-tunnel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
