<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; Springfestatx</title>
	<atom:link href="https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:20:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The child showed his talent at the age of 2 years</title>
		<link>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/the-child-showed-his-talent-at-the-age-of-2-years/</link>
					<comments>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/the-child-showed-his-talent-at-the-age-of-2-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guinness World Records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weird news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When a one-and-a-half-year-old child walks around, busy watching cartoons on his phone whenever he gets the chance, it is surprising that a child of the same age can speak and see the English alphabet quickly. But it really happened. Isla McNabb, from Kentucky, USA, has signed up as the youngest member of the high-IQ society ... <a title="The child showed his talent at the age of 2 years" class="read-more" href="https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/the-child-showed-his-talent-at-the-age-of-2-years/" aria-label="More on The child showed his talent at the age of 2 years">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When a one-and-a-half-year-old child walks around, busy watching cartoons on his phone whenever he gets the chance, it is surprising that a child of the same age can speak and see the English alphabet quickly. But it really happened.</p>



<p>Isla McNabb, from Kentucky, USA, has signed up as the youngest member of the high-IQ society Mensa at the age of two.</p>



<p>According to Guinness World Records, Isla McNav scored 99 out of 100 points on the Stanford-Benet Intelligence Scale, which measures the intelligence of 2-year-old children.</p>



<p>Mensa is the world&#8217;s largest high-level intelligence society. To become a member of this society, one must have a score of 98 percent on an intelligence scale.</p>



<p>Isla McNav&#8217;s father, Jason, told Guinness World Records that by the age of 7 months, she could identify pictures by looking at books. At the age of 1, he begins to learn color names, numbers and the alphabet.</p>



<p>On Isla&#8217;s second birthday, her aunt gave her an erasable tablet. Sekha Jason wrote the word &#8216;Red&#8217; in English one day. To everyone&#8217;s surprise, Isla was able to spell and read the word.</p>



<p>Then the names of different colors are written. Isla read them aloud without hesitation.</p>



<p>Isla was enrolled in Mensa by her parents to keep her child&#8217;s talent alive. According to Jason, the biggest advantage of Mensa, an international non-profit organization, is that it is an organization of talent. Isla is now in preschool.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/the-child-showed-his-talent-at-the-age-of-2-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>41 workers came out one by one from the blocked tunnel</title>
		<link>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/41-workers-came-out-one-by-one-from-the-blocked-tunnel/</link>
					<comments>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/41-workers-came-out-one-by-one-from-the-blocked-tunnel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the tunnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/?p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tuesday night around eight o&#8217;clock. Jharkhand laborer Vijay Horo was the first to come out of the blocked tunnel in Uttarkashi, Uttarakhand on a wheeled stretcher. In a moment, victory cheers started around him. Chief Minister Pushkar Singh Dhami wore the northerner around his neck. Union minister former army chief VK Singh was the witness. ... <a title="41 workers came out one by one from the blocked tunnel" class="read-more" href="https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/41-workers-came-out-one-by-one-from-the-blocked-tunnel/" aria-label="More on 41 workers came out one by one from the blocked tunnel">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Tuesday night around eight o&#8217;clock. Jharkhand laborer Vijay Horo was the first to come out of the blocked tunnel in Uttarkashi, Uttarakhand on a wheeled stretcher. In a moment, victory cheers started around him. Chief Minister Pushkar Singh Dhami wore the northerner around his neck. Union minister former army chief VK Singh was the witness. They pulled Vijay to their chest. That photo was caught in the media. The whole country breathed a sigh of relief after the anxiety was over. 17 consecutive days of continuous work is successful.</p>



<p>It was possible to bring out 41 people one by one before half past nine. All the rescue team including Chief Minister Dhami said that every worker is healthy. Their morale is also strong.</p>



<p>The chief minister himself raised the light of hope on Tuesday afternoon. This tunnel collapse was the most difficult challenge of his political life. 17 days ago on November 12, the 4.5 km tunnel collapsed. 41 workers from different states were trapped in it. From that day and night, various organizations were engaged in rescue work. Machines were brought from abroad. In came the experts who conduct rescue operations in such disasters. The attention of the entire country turned to this area at the foot of the Himalayas.</p>



<p>The news of the auger drilling machine brought from the United States becoming ineffective came as a big bad news for the countrymen who were in the swing of hope and despair. Foreign experts said that Christmas will come before the end of the new rescue phase. But the impossible was achieved within two days. The workers of the country cleared the tunnel manually with shovels and trowels and installed two and a half feet diameter concrete pipes. An iron pipe is installed in it. Through that pipe, disaster management personnel reached the stranded workers earlier in the evening. According to their advice, the arrested workers were dragged out one by one by putting them on a wheel stretcher. The prayers of the whole country were successful.</p>



<p>The rescued workers were first taken to the local hospital. A special ward has been opened there. All kinds of medical facilities have been kept. A helipad has been constructed next to the district hospital, so that any worker can be flown to the All India Institute of Medical Sciences in Hrishikesh.</p>



<p>After the successful completion of the rescue, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said in a message on social media, &#8220;This rescue has left everyone in the country emotional. I would like to say to the detained friends, your patience and courage have inspired all of us. After a long wait, they will be reunited with their families, it is a great relief. The patience and courage shown by their family during this difficult time is unparalleled.&#8217;</p>



<p>Union Road Development Minister Nitin Gadkari said that it has been decided to check the status of all the under-construction tunnels in the country. He said, the country learned a lot from this disaster.</p>



<p>This fact was also learned, where the machine failed, the infamous workers of India brought incredible success. Risking their lives in adverse conditions, they have managed to do the impossible by removing the collapse of the tunnel by hand and laying the pipe.</p>



<p>Despite the resolution of the rescue operation, the larger question remains. It has made the people of the country face the question of how rational the development by destroying nature is. The tunnel collapse that left so many workers dead is part of Prime Minister Narendra Modi&#8217;s &#8216;Char Dham&#8217; project. The project aims to connect the state&#8217;s four main pilgrimage sites of Kedarnath, Badridham, Gangotri and Yamunotri by building all-season roads and widening conventional roads for devout Hindus in Uttarakhand. But while doing so, the countrymen may have to face the fury of nature, this collapse indicated that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/41-workers-came-out-one-by-one-from-the-blocked-tunnel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tiger count has started in West Bengal&#8217;s Sundarbans</title>
		<link>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/tiger-count-has-started-in-west-bengals-sundarbans/</link>
					<comments>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/tiger-count-has-started-in-west-bengals-sundarbans/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the environment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/?p=10</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The tiger count has started in the Sundarbans of West Bengal on Monday. This calculation will start with camera trapping. For this, 1 thousand 464 cameras are being installed in Sundarbans. This camera will take pictures of tiger movement in Sundarbans. The forest department will review the images to determine how many tigers there are ... <a title="Tiger count has started in West Bengal&#8217;s Sundarbans" class="read-more" href="https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/tiger-count-has-started-in-west-bengals-sundarbans/" aria-label="More on Tiger count has started in West Bengal&#8217;s Sundarbans">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The tiger count has started in the Sundarbans of West Bengal on Monday. This calculation will start with camera trapping. For this, 1 thousand 464 cameras are being installed in Sundarbans. This camera will take pictures of tiger movement in Sundarbans. The forest department will review the images to determine how many tigers there are in the Sundarbans of West Bengal, India. However, according to the 2022 survey, there are currently 100 Bengal tigers in the Sundarbans.</p>



<p>50 forest personnel have been given special training at Sajnekhali Forest Department to install trap cameras for tiger census. The installation of the camera started yesterday. And it will end on Thursday.</p>



<p>Jones Justin, deputy field director of the Sundarban Tiger Project, told reporters that India has 51 tiger reserves. Sundarban Tiger Reserve is the 31st. There are now 100 tigers in this Sundarbans. Tiger census has been started again yesterday. However, in 1987, the Sundarbans, located on the land of West Bengal and Bangladesh, was declared a World Heritage by UNICEF. With that aim, the tiger census of the West Bengal part of the Sundarbans has also started.</p>



<p>Jones Justin also said that 732 locations have been selected for the census in the Indian Sundarbans and are being installed with sophisticated trap cameras. This automatic camera using infrared technology will take pictures of tiger movement for 35 consecutive days. After 35 days, the camera will be opened and the forest officials will analyze the images captured by the camera to ascertain how many tigers are moving in the forest.</p>



<p>In this Sundarbans of West Bengal, there is the Bengal Tiger, the king of Sundarbans. 100 Bengal tigers and other animals are found here. Although the Bengal tiger lives in India, Bangladesh, Nepal and Bhutan. There are now 100 Bengal tigers in the Sundarbans. 66 percent of the world&#8217;s Sundarbans falls in Bangladesh and 34 percent in West Bengal, India.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/tiger-count-has-started-in-west-bengals-sundarbans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
