<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>child &#8211; Springfestatx</title>
	<atom:link href="https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/tag/child/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:20:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The child showed his talent at the age of 2 years</title>
		<link>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/the-child-showed-his-talent-at-the-age-of-2-years/</link>
					<comments>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/the-child-showed-his-talent-at-the-age-of-2-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guinness World Records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weird news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When a one-and-a-half-year-old child walks around, busy watching cartoons on his phone whenever he gets the chance, it is surprising that a child of the same age can speak and see the English alphabet quickly. But it really happened. Isla McNabb, from Kentucky, USA, has signed up as the youngest member of the high-IQ society ... <a title="The child showed his talent at the age of 2 years" class="read-more" href="https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/the-child-showed-his-talent-at-the-age-of-2-years/" aria-label="More on The child showed his talent at the age of 2 years">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When a one-and-a-half-year-old child walks around, busy watching cartoons on his phone whenever he gets the chance, it is surprising that a child of the same age can speak and see the English alphabet quickly. But it really happened.</p>



<p>Isla McNabb, from Kentucky, USA, has signed up as the youngest member of the high-IQ society Mensa at the age of two.</p>



<p>According to Guinness World Records, Isla McNav scored 99 out of 100 points on the Stanford-Benet Intelligence Scale, which measures the intelligence of 2-year-old children.</p>



<p>Mensa is the world&#8217;s largest high-level intelligence society. To become a member of this society, one must have a score of 98 percent on an intelligence scale.</p>



<p>Isla McNav&#8217;s father, Jason, told Guinness World Records that by the age of 7 months, she could identify pictures by looking at books. At the age of 1, he begins to learn color names, numbers and the alphabet.</p>



<p>On Isla&#8217;s second birthday, her aunt gave her an erasable tablet. Sekha Jason wrote the word &#8216;Red&#8217; in English one day. To everyone&#8217;s surprise, Isla was able to spell and read the word.</p>



<p>Then the names of different colors are written. Isla read them aloud without hesitation.</p>



<p>Isla was enrolled in Mensa by her parents to keep her child&#8217;s talent alive. According to Jason, the biggest advantage of Mensa, an international non-profit organization, is that it is an organization of talent. Isla is now in preschool.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://springfestatx.utexas.edu/the-child-showed-his-talent-at-the-age-of-2-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
